Brecht Devleesschauwer PhD DVM MVSc MStat

Senior epidemiologist · Coordinator national burden of disease studies Sciensano, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health brecht.devleesschauwer@sciensano.be | brecht.cbra.be Rue Juliette Wytsmanstraat 14, 1050 Brussels, Belgium | +32 2 642 5035

Personal statement

The common goal of my research activities is to quantify the true impact of diseases and health inequalities, and to make model-based evaluations of prevention and control. I have developed and implemented the computational framework for estimating the global burden of foodborne disease, as an active member of the World Health Organization Foodborne Disease Burden Epidemiology Reference Group (WHO/FERG). Currently, I am implementing a Belgian national burden of disease study.

My research activities have led to more than 100 peer-reviewed scientific publications in national and international journals. My scientific expertise in burden assessment, risk assessment and health economics has been recognized through invitations to various national and international expert groups, including the Belgian Superior Health Council, the Belgian Food Safety Authority, and EFSA, WHO and FAO.

Education

2015 PhD Veterinary Sciences; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE
PhD Public Health; Université catholique de Louvain, Brussels, BE
2014 MSc Statistics; Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Louvain, BE
2010 MSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE
2007 BSc Veterinary Medicine; Ghent University, Merelbeke, BE

Employment

2018-	Visiting professor, advanced epidemiology; UCL, Brussels, BE
2018-	Visiting professor, risk analysis; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2016-	Senior epidemiologist; Sciensano, Brussels, BE
2016-18	Guest lecturer, health economics; UCL, Brussels, BE
2015-16	Assistant scientist, global food safety and zoonoses; UF, Gainesville, USA
2015	Post-doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE
2013-14	Consultant; World Health Organization, Geneva, CH
2010-15	Doctoral researcher; UGent, Merelbeke, BE & UCL, Brussels, BE

Mentoring and supervision

2 PhD students (2 ongoing) \cdot 36 MSc students (10 ongoing) \cdot 8 BSc students (0 ongoing)

Scientific output

6 book chapters \cdot 106 peer-reviewed publications

Google Scholar metrics: 2641 citations \cdot h-index 23 \cdot i10-index 51